- Hey, what's up, I'm Tom.
- I'm Zendaya.
- Jon.
- I'm Sadie.
- I'm Jacob.
- And today, with the cast of
"Spider-Man: Brand New Day,"
we are taking GQ's pop quiz.
[fun music]
- [Host] Round one, general comic trivia.
- Oh, no.
- [Host] What iconic line did
Uncle Ben say to Peter Parker?
- Aw, dammit.
- "With great power comes
great responsibility."
- [Host] Perfect.
- Fair and square.
- [Host] Next question,
who created Spider-Man?
- Aw, damn.
- Aw, shit.
- Stan Lee and Steve Ditko.
- [Jacob] Wow.
- [Host] Point for Tom.
- [Jacob] Dammit.
- [Host] What super villain
does Ned Leeds become in the comics?
- The Hobgoblin.
- [Host] That's correct.
- Win today.
- Really?
- Hobgoblin.
- Win today.
- [Host] It's gonna get harder, guys.
What did Mary Jane say
to Peter the first time-
- "Face it, tiger, you won?"
Like, "face it, tiger, face it, tiger."
- [Host] Half, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna, I'm gonna hold on.
If someone can the full sentence.
- "You hit the jackpot.
Face it, tiger, you hit the jackpot."
- [Host] There you go, that's
correct, point to Zendaya.
- Really did.
- [Host] All right.
Which issue of "The Amazing Spider-Man"
did The Punisher first appear?
- Oh, I don't know, I actually don't know.
- Wait, which what?
- [Host] Which issue of
"The Amazing Spider-Man"
did The Punisher first appear?
- Over to you.
- 143.
- [Host] 129.
- That was good though.
- Ballpark.
That was in the ballpark.
- Pretty close.
- [Host] Pretty close.
Last question in round one.
Who wrote the original comic's
run of "Brand New Day?"
- Oh damn.
- We should all know this.
- Embarrassing, we love you.
- We love you.
- [Host] The answer is-
- Someone from Sony.
Oh, go on.
- [Host] Dan Slott.
- Dan Slott.
- Sorry, Dan.
- Shout out.
- Shout out Dan.
- [Host] Round two, this is MCU,
sort of wider MCU multiverse knowledge.
- Nice, nice.
- Uh oh.
- [Host] What high school
did Peter, MJ and Ned attend?
- Midtown.
- [Host] Full title?
- High.
- Midtown High.
- Oh, sorry, sorry.
- [Host] I'll accept it.
- Midtown School of
Science and Technology.
- Oh, Midtown, yeah, okay.
- Science and Technology.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- [Host] I'll accept it.
Question two, what did
Peter say to Dr. Strange
after introducing himself
in "Avengers: Infinity War?"
- Oh, I don't know.
- I say, oh, we're using,
oh no, no, we're making our,
we're making our used up names.
Used up names?
- "We're using our made-up names."
- That's what I was trying to say.
- You were like jumbling,
bro, you were stumbling.
- I'm so tired.
- You can give it to him.
- We're making our used up names.
- I just was helping.
- Why do I keep?
We're making our-
- We're using.
- "We're using our made-up
names," there you go.
- [Host] I think I'm gonna
have to give to Zendaya
because you got it correct.
- It's a half, maybe we can split it.
- Yeah, you're right.
- [Host] In "Spider-Man: No Way Home."
- Oh yeah.
- [Host] What did Peter
3, Andrew Garfield,
think the Avengers were?
Tom.
- A band.
- [Host] That's correct.
- You wanna contribute Jon at some point?
- I'm there, I'm-
- He's coasting.
- Yeah, I'm sending good vibes.
- "I'm sending good vibes."
- [Host] What pizza place
did Peter Parker work
in the Sam Raimi "Spider-Man 2?"
- It didn't even go off.
Joe's Pizza.
- [Host] That is correct,
Jacob, you're on the board.
- Bang.
- [Host] What villains
did Peter Parker fight
in "The Amazing Spider-Man 2?"
- Aw, man.
- [Host] Tom.
- Rhino, Electro, Green
Goblin and that's it, right?
- [Host] That's it, that's it, you got it.
- I was gonna say, there's-
- There might have been another
one, yeah, right, right.
- [Host] What was the
name of Spider-Man's mecha
in the Japanese television series?
- His mecha suit.
- [Host] Mecha droid.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Mecha Droid?
- [Host] Leopardon.
- Oh.
I would not have got that.
- [Host] It was a weird show, guys.
- It's a deep cut.
- Yeah, that's a deep cut.
- [Host] Round three, this
is production knowledge.
Who filmed Tom Holland's audition video?
- Let's go.
Let's go.
- You know what, I it it first.
I'm gonna let you have this though.
- Thank you, you're so awesome.
Jonathan Edward Bernthal.
- Hey, let's go, let's go.
- [Host] We'll give it to Jon.
- I got that last.
That's so pathetic.
- [Host] What did Willem DaFoe wear on set
to prevent his appearance
in "Spider-Man: No Way Home"
from being leaked?
- I honestly forgot.
- [Host] I think that was
Zendaya, that was you.
- Everyone wore cloaks.
- [Jacob] Yeah.
- [Host] Who played Miles Morales's uncle
in "Spider-Man: Homecoming?"
- [Jacob] Aw man.
- Donald Glover.
- [Host] That's correct.
Name both of Tom's stunt doubles.
Jacob.
- Dave and Luke.
- Yeah, that's technically correct.
- That's technically correct.
- That is technically correct
'cause there has been a
bunch of stunt doubles.
- And there's more.
- And Chris.
- Yeah, right, other ones
from the other movies as well.
- But that is, that's technically correct.
- We've had a lot but yeah,
that's technically correct.
Yeah.
- [Host] Give it to Jacob.
All right, what two other Marvel projects
has "Spider-Man: Brand New Day"
director Destin Daniel Cretton directed?
- "Wonder Man" and "Shang-Chi."
- [Host] That's correct.
- That was kind of close.
- [Host] It was close, it was close.
- I don't know.
I'll let you have it though.
- Thanks.
- [Host] What show had Spider-Man's first
live action appearance?
- It's that TV show, isn't it?
- [Host] You're on the right track.
- He had his own TV show.
- Yeah, I just don't
know was it was called.
- It was just called "The
Amazing Spider-Man," right?
- [Host] "The Electric Company."
- Wrecked.
The way that you replied was like,
it was like really close-
- It's not that.
- [Host] It was a TV show.
- Right, right.
- Guy's like, no, right, yeah.
- [Host] Okay, so this is finish the line.
So basically, I'm not
gonna tell you who said it
but if you can figure out
what the second half of the line is.
- Okay.
- [Host] Buzz in.
"You know, I'm something of."
- [Both] "A scientist myself."
- But he, he, I didn't hit it fast enough.
- [Host] Yeah, I think Tom got it.
"That's my secret, Cap."
- What?
- [Host] "That's my secret, Cap."
"That's your secret, Cap."
- You say that?
- I didn't say that.
- [Host] You didn't say
that, no one here said that.
- Something Tony Stark would say?
- "It's my secret, Cap."
- But is it Spider-Man specific?
- No, I don't think so.
- [Host] It's wider MCU.
- Yes.
- [Host] It's someone that
is in this movie said this.
- Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, it's Mark Ruffalo.
It's Mark Buffalo, the Hulk.
He says, "It's time you get angry"
and he goes, "that's my
secret, Cap, I'm always angry"
and then he goes-
- [Host] There you go, that's correct.
It's a point to Tom.
- That was good.
- [Host] Here's another one.
"One batch, two batch."
- "Penny and dime," let's go.
- Damn, I would've never known.
- [Host] That's another point for Jon.
- It's crazy when that happens, isn't it?
- [Host] Next line,
"The power of the sun."
- "In the palm of my hand."
- [Host] That's correct,
Otto Octavius, awesome.
- Oh yeah, when he's
making like that thing.
- [Host] "If you're
nothing without this suit."
- "Then, then you shouldn't have it."
- [Host] That's right, Tony Stark.
- Yes.
Bang, Iron Man.
- [Tom] Well done.
- [Host] "I resent that.
Slander is spoken."
- Whoa.
- Can we hear it again?
- [Host] Absolutely, "I resent that.
Slander is spoken."
- I don't know.
- [Host] I'll give you a hint.
Another line this person
typically says like,
"I trust my barber."
- What the fuck?
- [Host] "Give me pictures of Spider-Man."
- Oh, it's J. Jonah Jameson.
- Yeah but what does he say though?
- And the line is?
- [Host] In print, it's libel.
- Spider-Man wasn't attacking the city.
He was trying to save it, that's slander.
- It is not, I resent that.
Slander is spoken.
In print, it's libel.
- You don't trust anybody,
that's your problem.
- I trust my barber.
- I would never have got that.
- So nobody gets a point,
you're supposed to finish it.
- [Host] I'm trying to mess with you guys.
- Yeah, I see.
- [Host] Round five is we're gonna have
a draw Spider-Man competition.
- Sadie, you gotta at
least win this one, bro.
You gotta hit this one.
- [Host] Sadie, I believe in you.
I'm gonna give you guys a minute.
- Oh okay.
- [Host] All right, in
three, two, one, go ahead.
- He's already going.
I made a bad shape, I made a bad shape.
- Nice.
- [Tom] Oh shit.
- Oh my God.
- Fucking this up.
- Aw, it's going so sideways.
- "Sideways."
- I fucked this up already.
- [Host] 10, nine, eight-
- He also wears little boots too kind of.
- Oh yeah, his little boots.
- Boots are going.
- [Host] Five, four, three, two, one.
All right, pencils down, everybody.
- I don't want to.
- Okay.
- [Zendaya] I like the buildings.
- Yeah, the buildings, actually, the webs.
I like the spread of webs.
- And it's got a scene.
- Yeah, it makes more sense.
- A little abstract, you know?
- Jacob, let me see what you got.
- [Zendaya] Okay.
- [Jon] You definitely won.
- Yeah, I think Sadie
might have killed it, yeah.
- [Tom] I think Sadie wins that.
- No.
- Yeah, the web-
- We just went with the belt.
- Yeah.
- Just the belt.
- A simplified suit if you will.
- I was like, do you even wear a belt?
- That's really good.
- That's a really great one.
Actual symbol of the-
- I like yours.
- It's bad, I started with
this and then I saw Zendaya's
and I tried to get the eyes different.
- The grand formation.
- Yeah.
- [Host] By vote, who do you think won?
Is it Sadie?
- Sadie.
- For sure.
- [Host] Sadie?
- There was so much detail.
- And there's way more to it, yeah.
- 'Cause I gave up.
- [Host] Well, Jacob breaks the set.
I'm gonna give Sadie the
point by Democratic vote.
So guys, this is the rapid
fire round, last round.
How many Spider-Man films are there,
films starring Spider-Man?
- Eight.
Nine.
Nine, there's nine.
- [Host] There are technically 14.
- Damn 'cause there's like animated ones.
- Yeah, not just the
live action ones, yeah.
- [Host] Who plays Spider-Man 2099
in "Into the Spider-Verse?"
- [Jacob] I don't know what his name is.
- It's the guy with the big daggers.
- The punk one?
- No, no, he's like the big mashing one.
- Like who plays him?
- Like who plays or-
- [Host] Who does the voice?
- Who does the voice.
- [Host] I'll give you a hint.
He is in "Star Wars" and "Dune"
and "Inside Llewyn Davis."
- Oh.
- [Jacob] He's a big guy.
- Why am I all of a sudden my
brain is not, cannot function?
- Help me.
- On vacation with each other.
- Oscar Isaac.
- [Host] Oscar Isaac,
I'll give it to Zendaya.
- Yeah.
- [Host] Where is Peter Parker from?
- Queens.
- [Host] Queens.
Sadie, you were close, but.
- Sorry, Sadie.
- It's all right, no, no, no, you take it.
- [Host] Next question is what
was Peter Parker's first line
in "Captain America: Civil War?"
Tom.
- "Fine."
- [Host] "Hey, May."
- Fu.
Fu.
- Yes, you're right.
"Hey, May" then I say "fine"
and then I say something
like "there's a crazy car
parked outside" and then I see-
- Nice Peter Parker voice.
- Thanks.
- Robert Downey Jr.
- [Host] The next question is
what was the last thing
Peter said to Tony Stark
"in Avengers: Infinity War?"
Zendaya.
- "I don't wanna go, I don't wanna go"
and then we've been through this.
- Nope.
- It's not "I don't wanna go?"
- [Host] Tom, buzz in.
- I say, "I'm sorry."
- [Host] Perfect, point for Tom.
- He goes, not you.
- [Host] And this one's a toughie.
When is the first time, technically,
that Spider-Man appeared alongside
the X-Men in live action?
- Wait, wait, sorry?
- Technically?
- [Host] When is the first
time Spider-Man appeared
in live action alongside the X-Men?
- No idea.
- Is it when he like went
onto their set one time
and he like, and it was
like a joke, was it?
- [Host] Jacob, that is 100%.
- Was that the one?
Yeah.
- How do you know that?
- Yeah, well, I remember
watching this video
because I was up late at night
and one of them was like a random fact
about like 2002 movies
and they were doing it
at the same time, right?
They were like filming the same
time or something like that?
- [Host] There were filming
around the same time, yeah,
and then it's a blooper on the DVD extra.
- Yes.
- Wait.
[everyone laughing]
I am completely in the wrong movie.
I am so sorry.
- [Host] Wow, Jacob.
I didn't think anyone was gonna get that.
- That was good.
- [Host] All right, so-
- I should win though.
- [Host] I mean, for that alone.
The final score is Sadie with one point.
Jon, you have two points.
Jacob, you came in with four points.
Zendaya, you have a total of seven points.
And Tom, you win this pop quiz
with a total of 10 points.
You are the winner of the GQ pop quiz.
- Boo.
- [Jacob] Boo.
- I've been playing this
character for 10 years.
It's the pride of my life.
Seems like you guys have got to do
a little bit more research
before you grace the sets
yet again.
Thank you.
- I don't know.
- I don't know about that, yeah.
- I feel like we can
run a few things back.
- Yeah, for sure.
- I could have gotten a
couple more, you know?